

### TAM LE

2386 Trafalgar Dr, Biloxi, MS 39531 ♦ Tam.Le@usm.edu ♦ 228.273.5531

Possess over 4 years of direct customer services within variety of major fields (waitress, tailoring, and cash register clerk), including almost 2 years in accounting field; well-versed in office and administrative assistant work, fast-learner and effective in multitasking; maintaining good communication skills in both teamwork and customers' services; passionate about analyzing data, and enthusiasm for team-building.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science in Business Administration in Accounting** 

♦ Anticipated Graduation: Fall, 2018

The University of Southern Mississippi, Long Beach, MS ◆ Phi Theta Kappa Hornor Society

**Bachelor of Science in Applied Computer Science** 

The University of Southern Mississippi, Long Beach, MS

◆ Anticipated Graduation: Fall, 2020

**Associate of Arts** GPA: 3.67

♦ Graduated: December, 2016

Mississippi Gulf Coast Community College, Gulfport, MS ◆ Vice President List, Phi Theta Kappa Hornor Society

#### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- Bilingual: fluent in both English and Vietnamese
- Proficient in both Windows OS and Mac OSX, Microsoft Office, POS system, Moroe System Calculator
- Associate with Accounting Softwares: HCA (Equivalent to QuickBook), and ProSeries (Tax Preparating)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graves & Oberlies PLLC (October 2016 to Present) ♦ Bookkeeper & CPAs' Assistant

- Multitasking: bookkeeping, tax preparing, CPAs' assistant, administrative assistant, and front-desk duties
- Bookkeeping works: input monthly checks, reconcile monthly bank statements, and post monthly journal entries for: hotels, battery wholesaler, building contractors, clinics, beauty salon, and restaurants
- CPAs' assistant and tax-preparator work: familiar with tax payments and reports on <a href="www.dor.ms.gov">www.dor.ms.gov</a> and assist CPAs to prepare individual income tax through ProSeries
- Administrative works: organize files and folders monthly and annually, answer phone call and schedule
  appointments, receiving mails, maintaining and updating clients' information lists, preparing and sending
  annual holiday cards

#### Men's Wearhouse (April 2014 to October 2016) ♦ Professional Tailoring

- Minimal supervision, self-managed customers' pick-up schedules
- Prepared yearly alteration supplies' report and maintained monthly supplies' ordering forms
- High rated customer comments in providing good services and qualified alteration
- Multitasked: alteration works, checked defects or damage clothes, repaired sewing machines, and provided individual fitting services

#### Tokyo Express & Kim Long Restaurant (October 2013 to March 2014) ♦ Food Server/Waitress & Cashier

- Operated the frontline cash register, and prepared brief daily budget summaries
- Maintained inventory and reported the exact amount to supervisor for future supplies' orders
- Offered variable customer services: receive orders, provide suggestions, and serving in-and-out foods
- Maintained a positive atmosphere for customers and a productive environment for coworkers

# **Retrospective:**

## • Things happened as expected:

Because I have met Ms. Jona Burton several times before the class started to fix my resume, I did not have any problem with creating my resume. Moreover, I have finished and submitted everything before the deadline.

### • Things went wrong:

The lack of computer science background caused myself some misunderstanding about the first sprint requirement. I did not really understand the progress of how to use sprint for planning and tracking on the project. I misunderstood about the sprint capacity, task lists and time estimates. Because the understanding was very unclear, I think I did it in an opposite way at first. Without the explanation of the instructor, I might turn in the wrong Sprint 1 Plan. Moreover, I uploaded my resume pdf file into the wrong branch on GitHub and need to re-uploaded two more times. Using GitHub is still very new for me, so it always consume much more time than my estimation.

### • If I have a chance to redo it, I will change:

After finished Sprint 1 Plan, I'm having a better understanding about how to do the next sprint. So, if I needed to re-do this sprint in the future, there would be some changes that I want to adjust. First, I think it will be the better idea to finish one sprint set (sprint's minimum requirements, plan, and deliverable) in the same day. Second, since I am now feeling more comfortable to use GitHub, I think my time estimates will be more accurate than the first time.